# **AKANKSHYA DAS**

### **Product Developer**

Competent Product Developer with 5 years of experience and a proven track record of analytical acumen in identifying patterns and extracting valuable insights. Possesses diverse experience in liaising with the key stakeholders to identify & resolve business problem statement and deliver excellent results.



### **Work History**

### 2023-04 -Current

### IT Analyst

Tata Consultancy Services(Organisational movement from BT group), Bangalore, Karnataka

**Project Name :** Harlequins **Product :** EE Broadband

#### **Description**

The goal of this project is to work for BT client to build solutions and work on functional and non functional enhancements.

#### **Responsibilities**

- Working for EE broadband product and service delivery and management using Java, spring boot, Mongo db, Apache Kafka and Angular.
- Working on change requests and tech upgrade.

### 2021-09 -Current

### **Design Engineer Professional**

British Telecom

**Project Name :** Harlequins **Product :** EE Broadband

#### **Description**

The goal of this project is to provide a solution to the agents to log tickets raised by customers, resolve them, analyze the ticket trends and chat bot for customers to directly book new product, service request or log complains.

#### **Responsibilities**

- Working for EE broadband product and service delivery and management using Java, spring boot, Mongo db, Apache Kafka and Angular.
- Worked on replacement of Memcached, library for caching mechanism with Redis Sentinel for high availability and better performance.
- Working on dockerization and containerization of applications using docker and kubernetes.
- Worked in priority bug fixes, change requests and delivered them on time.
- Worked on security vulnerabilities by efficiently handing exceptions to restrict sharing sensitive information with the end user.



### Contact

#### E-mail

akankshyadas97@gmail.com



### **Skills**

JAVA / J2EE

Microservices

Spring Boot, Angular

**REST Api** 

SOAP webservice

Oracle 10g, mysql

Hibernate

Docker, Kuberenetes

Junit

JMS, Apache Kafka



### Education

2014-08 - 2018-04

### Bachelor of Technology: Information Technology

College of Engineering And Technology - OD GPA: 8.5

2018-09 - Senior Project Engineer 2021-09

Wipro Ltd

Project Name: RESTART Client: LATAM Airlines

#### Description

RESTART is implementation of CROAMIS (Cargo Reservations, Operations, Accounting and Management Information System) for LATAM Airlines which is next gen end-to-end cargo management system and handles cargo flight scheduling, shipment creation, dispatch, operation management and accounting.

#### Responsibilities

- Fixing of various performance issues identified by the end users and testing team
- Developing web-services (REST and SOAP) and web-clients to consume services exposed by various external systems with data validations.
- Resolving high priority critical bugs on time.
- Responsible for debugging live environment issues and providing RCA and fixes.
- Responsible for Log analysis to debug cross technologies issues.
- Experience in cloud deployments as product is hosted in azure,
  Oracle and AWS environments and providing different client presales demos.

## 2018-06 - Project Engineer 2018-09

Wipro Ltd

**Project Name : BLUEDART Client : Blue Dart Express** 

#### **Description**

Blue Dart Express is an Indian logistics company that provides courier delivery services. Aim of this project was to develop a website where users can log in, get an estimate amount of price for the shipment, book the pick up of the shipment and track them and provide feedback.

#### **Responsibilities**

- Worked for website development for BLUEDART using LIFERAY framework and Mayen.
- Involved in client side and server side validation using jQuery.
- Integration of new portlet.
- Writing controller using spring MVC.
- Creating Rest web service to fetch DTO using json.



- Elasticsearch ELK for log management: Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana.
- Redis Cluster vs Redis Sentinel.
- Docker and kubernetes implementaion.



- Endowed with Employee of the Quarter twice for dedicated work and in time delivery on quick notice.
- Received appreciation for four PRAGATI ideas for ideating and implementing innovative business solution for the customer.
- Received appreciation for successful Go-Live and early life support activities.